Omar Al Houssami

Full Stack Engineer

Work driven, qualified and motivated software engineer, experienced with Full stack web development using different stack technologies. I am driven to continuously learn and improve myself and my environment. Email: omar.houssami20@gmail.com Mobile: +961 76939283 GitHub: TshiSelle

EXPERIENCE

AstroLabs Remote ApprenticeshipMarch 2022 - Present

o Project Apollo - JavaScript open-database project (Full Stack).

- o Designed and implemented project Landing Page with React.JS (Front-End)
- Data collection via web scarping.

Geek Express Remote

Part-time March 2021 - April 2021

- Web Development tutoring for students of age 17+.
- Game Development tutoring with GDevelopment game engine for students of age 17+.
- o Developing STEM learning activities and hands-on material for classes.
- Monitored student growth to identify strengths and areas for improvement.

Projects

- Project Apollo JavaScript Open-Database (Work in progress) Research oriented, open source, open-database platform that provides the sources needed for developers to learn, practice, and improve their skills in one location. Tech: React.JS, Express.JS, Node.JS, MongoDB (MERN)(April '22)
- Project Eirene Therapeutic AI (Work in progress) The next step for self care therapy. Eirene provides support for people that require assistance to find therapists in their area and an AI model that can help them in their everyday life. Tech: React.JS, Express.JS, Python, Node.JS, MongoDB(January '22)
- Scam Protector The Protector scraps the data from a website that could be a possible scam by checking the requests and alerting the user of it's safety. Tech: Python(October '21)

EDUCATION

Beirut Arab University

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

Beirut, Lebanon August 2022

ACTIVITIES

CODEX Member

Beirut, Lebanon February 2019 - Present

BAU Computer Science Club

- Founder and current president.
- Attended meetings varying in topics from self-development to the flexibility of computer scientists during the advancement of technologies and how to catch up.
- Participated in Modern Cybersecurity educational and technical perspective workshop.
- Participated in eco-friendly development "Can the digital world be sustainable?" workshop by Dr. Luc -Sorel-Giffo.

Lebanese Scout Association

Beirut, Lebanon

Boy Scout Unit Leader

February 2017 - Present

- Organize group activities.
- Working with sponsors to fund charity events.
- Training members to become future leaders.
- Meeting with parents to discuss their children's situation and what to focus on at home.

SKILLS

 $React.JS \mid Node.JS \mid Python \mid Java \mid C \neq \mid C + + \mid Swift \mid MongoDB \mid PostgreSQL \mid Git$

Languages

English: Fluent Arabic: Native French: Elementary